Guide to the Herbert H. Hyman papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Herbert H. Hyman Papers,
1942-1985.
Hyman, Herbert Hiram, 1918-
7.14 linear feet (17 manuscript boxes).
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library New York, NY. 10027
6619504
Herbert H. Hyman (1918-1985), an expert on the science of polling, was a professor of sociology at both Columbia University (1951-1969) and Wesleyan University (1969-1985). His papers deal primarily with his professional research interests and projects, but also include some teaching materials. His files include budgets, code books, correspondence, course materials, drafts, grant files, proposals, surveys, and typescripts.
Biographical Note
Herbert H. Hyman was born in New York City on March 3, 1918.
Hyman received all of his degrees from Columbia University. He completed a bachelor's degree in 1939, a master's in 1940, and a PhD. in Social Psychology in 1942. During World War II, Hyman worked for the United States Government. At first, he worked as a Social Science Analyst for the Division of Program Surveys in the Department of Agriculture. From 1942-1944, he worked as a Public Opinion Analyst in the Surveys Division of the Officer of War Information. From 1942-1946, he was involved in the U.S. Strategic Bombing Survey of Germany and the Bombing Survey of Japan, and in 1947, he was a member of the Expert Mission on Public Opinion and Sociological Research, Army of Occupation, Japan.
In 1947, Hyman became a Senior Project Director at the National Opinion Research Center (NORC). He joined the faculty of Columbia University as an Associate Professor in the Department of Sociology in 1951, although he continued to work part-time at NORC until 1957. While at Columbia, Hyman chaired the Sociology Department (1965-1969) and served as the Associate Director for the University's Bureau of Applied Research (1957-1969). He also served as the Program Director for the United Nations Research Institute for Social Development in Geneva (1964-1965). From 1969 until his retirement, he was a professor of sociology at Wesleyan University. During his career, Hyman also held visiting professorships and lectureships at several institutions, including the Universities of California at Berkeley, Oslo, Ankara, Turin and Milan, Catania and Turin, Temple University, and MIT.
Hyman was the author of four books on public opinion polling, and is credited with helping to advance the science of polling. He is well-known as a survey researcher, and had strong interests in education, socialization, and attitude change. But as David Sills notes in his review of Surveying Social Research: Papers in Honor of Herbert H. Hyman, Hyman did not see survey work as a purely technical exercise. He felt that survey work was “both a method for obtaining information needed by policy makers and scholars and a form of ethnography - a way of enabling people to reveal their culture and their feelings to a researcher.”
Hyman married Helen Kandel, a freelance writer, in 1945. The couple had two sons, Alex and David, and a daughter, Lisa. Hyman died in China after suffering a heart attack in December 1985. He had traveled to the country to speak at a conference on “Uses of Sociology in Developing Countries” at Zhongshan University.
Scope and Content
The papers deal primarily with Hyman's professional research interests and projects, and include material on both published and unpublished projects. In general, Hyman grouped materials together by topic or project. The files also include some course, lecture and teaching materials; budgets, code books, correspondence, course materials, drafts, grant files, proposals, research, surveys, and typescripts.
The papers reflect Hyman's interest in education, socialization, and attitude change. They include files on research projects related to blind individuals, civil liberties, comparative survey research, desegregation in schools, public opinion, race and race relations, and widowhood. At the time of his death, Hyman was researching the history of survey research; there are several files related to the project.
Hyman often kept files on similar subjects or projects together in small groups. For example, the files on research projects include large sets of files on two topics. The first set of files relates to Hyman's research study on the blind, referred to in reports as “Communication, Perception and Social Behavior: Explorations in These Fundamental Processes through the Study of the Inter-group Relations and Attitudes of the Blind.” This project was started in the early 1960s at Columbia University. The files include code books, correspondence, proposals, and reports. Although Hyman produced several articles from the research, the unrest at Columbia University in 1968 caused the disruption and abandonment of the project.
The second set of files relates to the Office of War Information (OWI). These files include code books, correspondence, memoranda, reports, and background material. Although Hyman did work for the Surveys Division of OWI during World War II, it is clear from his correspondence that he also conducted research on this topic in the early 1980s. It is not clear if these materials document Hyman's research activity, his work at OWI, or both.
There are two items which appear to date from Hyman's time as a student: a course paper (1942) and a resource list of materials relating to Social Psychology written with Gardner Murphy. Both are in Box 2. Otherwise, the collection contains no material from Hyman's pre-professional activities.
A few files that contain biographical information and reviews of Hyman's work are filed in Boxes 5, 7, and 10. There are a few publicity photographs of Hyman in the "Personal Data" file in Box 7; otherwise, there are no photographs in the collection. The collection does not contain any material related to Hyman's personal life or interests.
Arrangement
The files have been left in the order in which Herbert Hyman stored them during his lifetime.
Subjects
Hyman, Herbert Hiram, 1918-; Blind--Research--United States.; Interviewing.; Political psychology.; Political socialization.; Public opinion polls.; Social psychology.; Social sciences--Research.; Social sciences--Methodology.; Social surveys.; Correspondence
Access Restrictions
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
This collection was donated by Mrs. Helen Kandel Hyman in 1989.
Finding aid in repository; folder level control.
- Files
  - Readings in Public Opinion, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    (In Turkish)
  - Collected Lectures: Introduction the Methodology of the Social Sciences, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Animals, 1948-1972 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Civil Liberties, circa 1946-1962 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Public Opinion, circa 1949-1962 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Texas Lecture on Communication and Integration, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Mass Communication, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    (Draft for book chapter and correspondence)
  - PSD and Later ISR (Institute for Social Research, University of Michigan), 1977-1982 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Voluntary Association, 1960-1977 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Handbook Chapter, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    (Hyman wrote an article for the Handbook of Political Psychology in 1973)
  - Strategies in Comparative Social Research, 1963 July (Box 1, Folder 11)
    (Inter-University Consortium for Political Research)
  - Prose Surveys--HH Memos, 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Political Socialization: A Study in the Psychology of Political Behavior, 1957-1958
    - Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Typescript (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Social Psychology--List of Teaching and Research Material, circa 1940s (Box 2, Folder 1)
    (Compiled by Gardner Murphy and Herbert Hyman)
  - Catholic Physicians and Birth Control/Experimental Selective Empanelling, 1964, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    (Proposal and correspondence)
  - An Outline for the Comparative Study of National Images of America, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    (Draft)
  - Historical Trends in the Study of Genius, 1942 January (Box 2, Folder 4)
    (Course paper)
  - Democratic Potential/Values Study, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    (Turkey)
  - An Experimental Study of Functional Autonomy, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    (Correspondence, typescript)
  - Material related to the U.S. Strategic Bombing Survey of Germany, 1944-1945 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Expert Informant Article, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Social Science Research Council--Comparative Sociological Research Committee, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Problems of Inducing Social Change: Some Implications for Education, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    (Lecture at the University of Michigan)
  - The Mysterious Case of Gini and Galvani: The Cause of Random Sampling Abetted by the Nonrandom Sampling of Scientific Information, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    (Correspondence; typescript)
  - 1976 Italy Sabbatical, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Stouffer Article for Dictionary of American Biography, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - 295-361, circa 1952-1972 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    (Includes teaching materials and a research proposal entitled, "Problems and Principles of Secondary Analysis of Survey Data: A Proposal for the Codification of Past Experience Leading to the Improved Utilization in the Future")
  - Anomie Paper, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Race, 1982-1985 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    (Research on school desegregation)
  - Secondary Analysis of Sample Surveys Sample Pages, circa 1972 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    (Book reviews)
  - Readings in Reference Group Theory and Research--Correspondence, 1966-1972 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Spencer--Budget, 1973-1975 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    (Grant for "The Enduring Effects of Education")
  - Survey Design, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    (Royalties for "Survey Design and Analysis")
  - Reference Group Book Royalties, 1966-1970 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - National Science Foundation (NSF)--Principles of Secondary Analysis Grant, 1969-1972 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Enduring Effects of Education Royalties, 1974-1985 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Sabbatical, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    (Related to research for "History of the Sample Survey Method of the United States")
  - Contract--Encyclopedia (Klineberg article), 1975-1978 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - 1971-1972 Italy--Papers, 1971-1973 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Civil Liberties Piece, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    (The piece is "England and America: Climates of Tolerance and Intolerance")
  - Arno Press Foreign Status, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    (Related to the reprinting of his dissertation)
  - Spencer, 1975-1978 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    (Related to "The Enduring Effects of Education")
  - John Reed--Lecture on South, Undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Unemployment, 1975-1979 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    (Related to "The Effects of Unemployment: A Neglected Problem in Modern Social Research")
  - Italy Survey Analysis Lectures and Comp. Survey Analysis MS, Undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Bob Smith Chapter and Manuscript, 1971-1984, (2 Folders) (Box 3, Folder 15-16)
    (Related to "Strategies in Comparative Survey Research," written for Quantitative Methods: Focused Survey Research and Casual Modeling)
  - Encyclopedia of Public Opinion, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    (This is related to "Opinion Measurement" written for the International Encyclopedia of Communications)
  - SOC 224, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Public Opinion Classes, 1971, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Proposal--University Linkage Program for Scandinavia, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Material on Various Courses, 1955-1968 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - SOC 295, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Bureau of Applied Social Research (BASR)/ORR, 1974-1985 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Social Conditions for Public Opinion, Undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
    (Typescript; Drafts)
  - Sociology Classes, 1954-1956, (2 Folders) (Box 4, Folder 6-7)
  - A Substitute for the Traditional Control Group in Evaluation Studies (with Charles Wright), 1959, Undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Political Institutions and Political Cultures, circa 1964 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    (Correspondence; drafts)
  - Hold--Valuable Correspondence--Pending, 1969-1975 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Civil Liberties Project, circa 1954 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Reference Groups File, 1963-1971, Undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Public Opinion/Political Culture, Undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - The Expanding Public, Undated, (2 Folders) (Box 5, Folder 2-3)
    (See the preceding Folder for a larger table of contents)
  - Personal Response Project, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    (Correspondence with R.A. McGonigal)
  - SOC 195 and 196, 1952-1955 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Public Opinion, 1975 Spring (Box 5, Folder 6)
    (Includes reading list; drafts of research writings)
  - Political Institutions and Political Cultures/The Expanding Public, Undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
    (Drafts; typescripts)
  - H. Hyman's Publication List, 1965-1968 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    (Includes correspondence)
  - HH--Sex Roles, Undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Social Structure and the Structure of Publics, Undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Public Opinion, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    (SOC 223)
  - University Linkage with Scandinavia, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Proposal for Senior Seminar, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Proposal for Research Project on the Social and Psychological Effects of Widowhood, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - SOC 206x (Previously 292) Secondary Analysis, 1977-1982 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Old Course Materials, 1954-1956 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Communication Research G6094y Reading List, Undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Public Opinion Course--Reading List, 1966 Spring (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Race Relations Experiment, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Secondary Analysis Proposal, 1968 February (Box 6, Folder 12)
    (Full title is "Problems and Principles of Secondary Analysis of Survey Data: A Proposal for Codification of Past Experience Leading to Improved Utilization in the Future")
  - Special Correspondence--References, Letters to Students, Etc., 1966-1969 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Survey Design--Guido Martinotti, 1966-1968 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    (Related to the Italian edition of "Survey Design and Analysis")
  - Reading List for G9073x (Evaluational Research), 1967 September (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous Reading Lists, 1965-1968 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Bob Smith MS, 1970, 1984-1985 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    (This is "Strategies in Comparative Survey Research, written for Quantitative Methods: Focused Survey Research and Casual Modeling")
  - Obits/Obituary Study, 1963-1964 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Overseasmanship, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    (Correspondence on Hyman's contribution to "Studying Politics Abroad: Field Research in Developing Areas")
  - Sociology 197, 1956, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Mixed Blood, 1966-1967 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - 1952 New York State Political Study, circa 1956 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    (Title of typescript is "New York State and the 1956 Presidential Election: A Survey Sample of Voters")
  - Editing Instructions and Codes--Hyman Political Survey (Confidential), 1956 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence May-June, 1964 March-July, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence with publisher, related to Secondary Analysis of Sample Surveys
    - Secondary Analysis, 1984-1985 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Wiley--Secondary Analysis Book, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Memorials--Stember, Dribble, Schmiedeck, 1980-1982 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    (Written by Hyman)
  - Reprints, circa 1984 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Wesleyan--Benefits, 1977, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    (Includes correspondence on retirement plans)
  - Consulting, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    (Related to a report evaluating a "Survey of Consumer Reactions to Three Reader's Digest Promotional Mailing Pieces")
  - Correspondence, 1969-1970, (2 Folders) (Box 7, Folder 11-12)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1984-1985 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Personal Data, 1952-1985, (2 Folders) (Box 7, Folder 14-15)
  - Correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Dr. Kandel's Publication, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Retirement Letter, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Hyman Personal Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - HHH Personal, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Psychology of Status Contract, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1969-1983, (2 Folders) (Box 8, Folder 6-7)
  - China Trip, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1961-1983 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Unidentified Binder, circa 1950 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Preface for Secondary Analysis, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Reading Lists Communications Research, circa 1957-1981 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - A Personal History of Survey Research, 1967-1985, (5 Folders) (Box 9, Folder 1-5)
  - Miscellaneous Notes to Check with Department, 1979-1982 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Stouffer, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - SSRC--pre-elect. 48 meas. Consumer wants wtc., 1948-1952 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Radvanyi--McCarthyism, 1954-1955, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - State Polls--University Centers (Specialized Centers), 1982-1983 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - A Personal History of Survey Research
    - Russell Sage, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - For General Intro (I) Intro to Part II, Undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
      (Ratings of the proposal)
    - Russell Sage Progress Reports and Budgets, 1983-1985 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Russell Sage Letter of Award and Budget, 1981-1984 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - The Rise of Survey Research: An Insider's Remembrance of Things Past (Address to New York Chapter of the American Association for Public Opinion Research), 1980 October (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - The Sample Survey: Its Nature, History, Utilization and Effects. A Preliminary Report to the National Science Board, 1979 February (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - "Public Opinion Research in Japan" from Opinion News, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - The Enduring Effects of Education
    - Research Proposal, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Papers Presented on, 1973-1974 (Box 10, Folder 3-4)
  - Reviews of Hyman's Work, circa 1959-1980 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Long Term Trends in Belief About the Characteristics of Women and Men: Study of social change by semi-secondary analysis of national surveys, 1973 November (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - The Enduring Effects of Education II: Effects in the Realm of Values: A Research Proposal to the Spencer Foundation, 1975 March 1 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - The Utility of the Sample Survey in the Study and Care of Epilepsy I. Design and Validation of the Method and Basic Findings on Prevalence, circa 1970s (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Working Papers and Memos--Encampment for Citizenship Evaluations/Hyman and Wright, 1955 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Experiment--Black Prestige Suggestion, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    (Social Research Curriculum Project--Research in Race Relations)
  - Reflections on the Development of Methodology (Unpublished), 1983 August (Box 10, Folder 11)
    (Written for Hyman's reception of the Helen Dinerman Memorial Award)
  - The Evolution of Heroes (People Magazine), 1984 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Civil Liberties, circa 1956 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    (Some of this relates to "England and America: Climates of Tolerance and Intolerance")
  - Russell Sage Foundation (Review of Irving Crespi Proposal), 1983 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence (Kenneth Langston), 1970 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous for Follow-up Study and Proposal (Widowhood), 1979-1983 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Texas Poll, circa 1979 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - The Sciences of Man, 1984-1985 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Coca-Cola, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    (Consultation work for Pepsi Challenge Commercials case)
  - Social Survey Manuscript, Undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Serendipity (Final Copy), Undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - PALIO, Undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Warner Studies, 1981-1982 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Japanese Survey Mission, 1947 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Otto Klineberg, 1975 October (Box 11, Folder 10)
    (Corrected Copy)
  - Civil Liberties, 1956 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    (Research Proposal)
  - USSBS Bombing Article, 1972-1981 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Survey Methodology--History--Daniel Katz and Steve Nelson, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Dan Katz File and Case Study, 1982-1983 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    (This is related to "A Personal History of Survey Research")
  - SRC December Revision, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    (The appears to be related to the Survey Research Center at the University of Michigan)
  - SRC Miscellaneous Items to check against manuscript and Dan's Case Study, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Files related to Blind Studies, circa 1963-1973
    - Professor Hyman's Grant, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Blind Article, 1963-1973 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Supplementary Report on Phase I of Communication, Perception and Social Behavior (Attitudes of the Blind), 1963 March 1 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Proposal to the National Science Foundation: Phase II of Research (Attitudes of the Blind), 1963 January, (2 Folders) (Box 12, Folder 4-5)
    - [Children's?] Sample, Undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Sample Blind Finished (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Blind--Mimeo Appendices (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Adult Blind North Occupational Choice (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Blind Occ./Manpower, circa 1967 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Untitled, (2 Folders) (Box 13, Folder 1-2)
    - Reliability, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence on Blind, 1963-1965 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Blind Materials, circa 1964 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Application for Conference Grant, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Draft--Blind Project (Box 13, Folder 7)
      (Appendix D)
    - Untitled (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Personal Blind, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence--Blind Study, 1962-1963 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Blind Study, (2 Folders) (Box 13, Folder 11-12)
    - HH Letter to M. Raeder, 1963 December 20 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - HH Memoranda, 1961-1963 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Untitled (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Sample Report (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - M. Raeder--Boston Report, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Sample Data New York, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - NORC (National Opinion Research Center) Correspondence on the Blind, circa 1964 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - New Orleans, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Boston, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Blind--North Carolina, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Essex County (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Children's Interview--Drafts and Pretest Questionnaires, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Blind Correspondence (General), 1963-1964 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Blind--Children's Study, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Atlanta, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Blind, New York, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Mimeos, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Blind Special Interest Items, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Untitled, 1961-1966 (Box 14, Folder 7)
      (Correspondence; Survey Designs)
    - Code Books
      - Adult Blind (Box 14, Folder 8)
      - Blind Children (Box 14, Folder 9)
      - Master Code Book: Blind Children (Box 14, Folder 10)
      - Adult Matched Sighted (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - Matched Parents (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - Matched Sighed Siblings (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - NORC White Blind Adult (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Office of War Information (OWI) Files, circa 1942-1946
    - Shipbuilding Background, 1942 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Surveys Division Memoranda # 46, 53, 53A, 53B, 99, 1943-1944 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Instruments Absenteeism Study, 1943 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - OWI, 1942-1944, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Material on Labor Surveys, 1942 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Surveys Division Memoranda #44, 54, 60, 1943 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - USSBS (US Strategic Bombing Survey of Germany), 1940s, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 2)